NATALIE DIXON | WEB DESIGNER & FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Phone: 07548282074 Email: natalie@nataliejdixon.com Web: www.nataliejdixon.com

SUMMARY

I'm a hybrid web designer/developer with some UX chops. I aim for clean, device-agnostic interfaces, maintainable CSS, and user experiences that are at once seamless and delightful. Working in a small Agile development team ensures I'm comfortable 'talking code', while my editorial/communications background means I bring plenty of soft skills to the table.

CORE SKILLS

UI/UX Design: Interviewing users, conducting research, creating user flows, icons, wireframes,

mockups and prototypes

Development: HTML5, CSS3, CSS pre-processors SASS and LESS, responsive frameworks

including Skeleton and Bootstrap. Experience of vanilla JavaScript, jQuery,

WordPress theming, HTML emails and task-runners such as Gulp.

Tools: Adobe Creative Cloud packages (Experience Designer, Photoshop, Illustrator,

InDesign and Acrobat), Visual Studio, Git version control, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint), Entourage. Fully competent on both PCs and Macs.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nov 2015 – present: Web Designer, Cezanne HR, London

Hybrid UI and UX role in an Agile context, working on the interface of a complex HR management web application:

- Creating user flows, wire-frames, mockups, prototypes and icons
- Leading user research (interviewing users and analysing feedback)
- Implementing designs in HTML5 and LESS CSS
- Introducing and maintaining a UI pattern library
- Working with developers to ensure a great match between user needs and functionality

Aug-Sept 2015: Freelance web projects, including

Barney's Bubble (<u>www.barneysbubble.com</u>)

Designed and built a website for a small home-stay business using HTML, SASS, Skeleton and WordPress. Produced custom vector artwork to brief.

Portfolio site (<u>www.nataliejdixon.com</u>)

Designed and built portfolio website using self-taught HTML, CSS, LESS, Skeleton and WordPress skills to create a responsive online platform.

Oct 2013-July 2015: Travel to Asia, Australia and New Zealand:

- Developing resilience, adaptability and excellent communication skills
- Freelancing as a graphic and web designer, building great working relationships with clients to create websites and marketing materials to briefs

July-Sept 2014: Assistant in Internal Communications, TIO, Darwin, Australia

Temporary role in Internal Communications. Duties included:

- Delivering campaigns across multiple communications channels
- Copy-writing and editing communications in line with internal branding
- Planning and agreeing a strategy with senior figures to lead a six-week campaign, coordinating branded emails with interview-based intranet articles

Jan 2013-Sept 2013: Assistant Editor – Asterix (book series), Orion Publishing Group, London

Contract position overseeing the update of a leading children's comic book series:

- Proofreading and checking visually complex material, including e-book files
- Liaising with internal and external contacts in the context of setting deadlines

Sept 2010-Jan 2013: Assistant Editor, Longtail Publishing, Kensington, London

Work for a bilingual business publisher:

- Creating page layouts, web graphics, adverts and other materials
- Coordinating the launch of a new website, providing feedback and collating content
- Copy-writing, copy-editing and proofreading
- Managing dual-language publications to tight deadlines, involving liaison with international freelancers, contributors, printers and translators
- Designing and producing a prototype for a promotional iPad App, rethinking content in line with altered user experience

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

2007-2010: BA Hons English, Trinity College, University of Cambridge – Class: 1st

An academically rigorous degree requiring advanced written communication skills.

Achieved a 1st in all three years.

2000-2007: Westcliff High School for Girls, Westcliff-on-Sea, Essex

• A-Levels: English (A), History (A), Politics (A) and Art (A)

GCSEs: 9 A*s including English Literature and Maths, 2 As

ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS

Sept 2016: Front End North (conference), Sheffield

Attended full-day conference on design, development and UX topics.

Oct 2013-July 2015: Personal development and boundary-pushing while travelling:

- Extensive multi-day trekking in the Himalayas, New Zealand and Vietnam
- Discipline-testing yoga and meditation courses in India and Thailand
- Working in non-English-speaking/unfamiliar contexts, including an Indian farm

Jan 2013-July 2013: Volunteer Designer, Nowhere festival

Designed the logo and general visuals for an arts festival, producing print-ready work to deadlines and technical specifications.

Jan 2011-July 2013: Volunteer Editor, Nowhere festival Survival Guide

Managed the production of a festival guide into five languages. Worked as part of a multilingual international team, voluntarily sourcing, editing and proofreading contributions and liaising with team members via meetings, phone-calls and emails.

General interests: Creative writing, digital art, painting, coding, fire performance.

References available on request